Guide to the Herbert L. Abrams Papers SC0858
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Herbert L. Abrams papers
circa 1950-2004
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Abrams, Herbert L.
Reagan, Ronald
SC0858
75.5 Linear Feet (57 boxes)
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Gift of Herbert L. Abrams 2007-2016.
Information about Access
Access: Materials are open to research use.
Biographical/Historical note
Herbert Abrams is a professor of radiology, emeritus, at the Stanford School of Medicine and a member-in-residence at CISAC [Center for International Security and Cooperation], where he directs the Project on Disabled Leadership. He was Professor and Director of Diagnostic Radiology at Stanford from 1960 to 1967, and was then appointed and served as Philip H. Cook Professor and Chairman of Radiology at Harvard University from 1967 to 1985. He returned to Stanford in 1985 as Professor of Radiology. Abrams was founding vice president of International Physicians for the Prevention of Nuclear War, which received the Nobel Peace Prize in 1985. He was also active for more than 20 years in Physicians for Social Responsibility.
Scope and Contents note
Papers pertaining to his medical teaching career include syllabi from Harvard Medical School Departments of Radiology and Continuing Education, 1982-1984; materials from Resident Seminars, 1956-1982; his reprints; and general professional papers which include correspondence, circa 1950-1971, and articles, talks, and conference materials, 1986-1988. The collection also includes research files and his writings on civil defense, the attempted assassination of Ronald Reagan, Yalta Conference of 1945, cognition and decision-making, decision-makers and Soviet leaders, nuclear accidents, effects of radiation, and presidential health.
Presidents -- United States -- Health.; Nuclear accidents.; Radiography, Medical -- Study and teaching.; Abrams, Herbert L.; Yalta Conference (1945).; Reagan, Ronald; Stanford University. School of Medicine; Abrams, Herbert L.; Harvard Medical School.; Reagan, Ronald
- Papers, Accession ARCH-2007-050
  - Harvard Medical School Departments of Radiology and Continuing Education Syllabi
    - Binder 1: Angiography 1983 (Box 1)
    - Binder 2: Cardiac Angiography 1984 (Box 1)
    - Binder 3: Computed Tomography 1982 (Box 1)
    - Binder 4: Therapeutic and Diagnostic Angio for 80's (Box 1)
    - Binder 5: CT and NMR Update 1984 (Box 1)
    - Binder 6: Angiography 1984 (Box 1)
    - Binder 7: Orthopedic Radiology 1984 (Box 1)
    - Binder 8: Ultrasound 1983 (Box 1)
    - Binder 9: Cardiac Angiography 1983 (Box 1)
    - Binder 10: CT and NMR Update 1983 (Box 1)
    - Binder 11: Clinical Nuclear Medicine 1984 (Box 1)
    - Binder 12: Coronary Angiography 1984 (Box 1)
    - Binder 13: Chest Disease 1984 (Box 1)
  - Personal Reprints
    General note
    Box 2 also contains one of reprints
    - Personal Reprints (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Personal Reprints (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Personal Reprints (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Personal Reprints (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Personal Reprints (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Personal Reprints (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Personal Reprints (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Personal Reprints (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Personal Reprints (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Personal Reprints (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Personal Reprints (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Personal Reprints (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Personal Reprints (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Personal Reprints (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Personal Reprints (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Resident Seminars
    - Binder 1: 1956-1958 (Box 3)
    - Binder 2: 1959-1961 (Box 3)
    - Binder 3: 1964-1965 (Box 3)
    - Binder 1: 1966-1967 (Box 4)
    - Binder 2: 1968-1969 (Box 4)
    - Binder 3: 1969-1970 (Box 4)
    - Binder 1: 1970-1971 (Box 5)
    - Binder 2: 1971-1972 (Box 5)
    - Binder 1: 1971-1972 (Box 6)
    - Binder 2: 1972-1973 (Box 6)
    - Binder 3: 1973-1974 (Box 6)
    - Binder 1: 1974-1975 (Box 7)
    - Binder 2: 1976-1977 (Box 7)
    - Binder 3: 1977-1978 (Box 7)
    - Folder: 1976-1976 (Box 7, Folder Hold)
    - Binder 1: 1978-1979 (Box 8)
    - Binder 2: 1979-1980 (Box 8)
    - Binder 3: 1979-1980 (Box 8)
    - Binder 1: 1980-1981 (Box 9)
    - Binder 2: 1980-1981 (Box 9)
    - Binder 3: 1981-1982 (Box 9)
    - Binder 4: 1962-1963 (Box 9)
  - Papers
    - Notable (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Natl. Cntr. for Health Care Tech: Policy & Progress (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - U.S. Health Policy Program (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Assembling New Technologies Computed Technology (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Health Problems of the Eighties (Kaiser morning meetings) (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Medical Technology—Bunker Material (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Cost Effective (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - MS. The Golden Era of Radiology (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Golden Age of Radiology Reference Material (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - References The Golden Age of Radiology: is there enough gold? (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Sharon (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Caldwell Lecture—Collateral Circulation Research and Studies (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Manuscript—Centripetal Spread of Endothermal Cell Mitotic Activity in the Artery (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Manuscript Angiography of the Adrenal Gland Chapter in Campbell's Urology. Abrams and Adams (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Manuscript Collateral Arterial Development and Renal Function in Experimental (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Manuscript Collateral Formation in the Coronary Circulation (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Collateral Vessel Formation: Isolation of a Transferable Factor Promoting Vascular Response Cuttingo et al. (Abrams) (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Medicine for the 21st Century, January 5-8, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Forum: Cal Poly State University Friday, January 17, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Radiology Grand Rounds Jan 23, 1986—5:30-6:30 p.m. (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - World Affairs Council—Feb. 5, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Speech You Can Make a Difference Feb 22, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Univ. of Cal: School of Nursing February 5, 1986 10:10-11:50 a.m. (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - CMA Annual Meeting February 28—March 1, 2 1986 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Society of Cardiovasc. & Interventional Radiology Feb. 14-16 & Feb. 17-20, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Society of Thoracic Radiology February 15-20, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Computer Professionals for Social Responsibility—March 1, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Bechtel Center: Speech March 6, 986 12:00-1:15—IPPNW & Nobel Award (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Long Island Jewish—Hillside Med Cntr: March 17 & 18, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Kaiser Lecture—April 1, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - IOM: Reception at UC/SF Monday, April 14, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - American Roentgen Ray Society April 14-18, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - Santa Clara College—April 21, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - SUNY Downst. Med. Cntr. Alumni Reunion—May 2-4, 1936 [sic, should be 1986] (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - Choices for Women in the Nuc. Age May 3, 1986 on nat. sec. iss. (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - AAMSI Congress May 8-10, 1986—Anaheim, CA (Box 10, Folder 36)
    - North American Society for Cardiac Radiology May 9-11, 1986 Boston (Box 10, Folder 37)
    - Assoc. of Univ. Radiologists May 4-9, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - Joint Mtg.: Jerusalem, Israel May 11-22, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - The Conference on the Danger of Nuclear War—Univ. of Brit. Colum.—Vancouver—May 26-30, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 40)
    - IPPNW Meeting: Kolmn May 29—June 2, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 41)
    - Coronary Angiography 1986: Brigham & Women's June 9-12, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 42)
    - Seminar: Professor Bershader June 26, 1986 8:00 p.m. (Box 10, Folder 43)
    - IPPNW Symposium on the Dangers & Prevention of Nuc. War: Sept. 14, 1986—Washington D.C. (Box 10, Folder 44)
    - Friday, Sept. 19, 1986 7:40 a.m. The Breakfast Club—Jewish Bus. + (Box 10, Folder 45)
    - Physician's Role in the Nuc Age Oct. 18, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 46)
    - Impact of New Imaging Technology October 23, 24, & 25, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 47)
    - Mil. Coll. Rad. & U. of Wisc: Milwaukee: Oct. 27, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 48)
    - Saturday, November 1, 1986 U of W—Seattle—PSR (Box 10, Folder 49)
    - Davis Lecture—Nov. 5, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 50)
    - American Heart Association 59th Sci Sess. Nov. 17-20, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 51)
    - PMT Advisory Board Comm. Mtg. Nov 21& 22, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 52)
    - Conjoint Committee on Diagnostic Imaging (Box 10, Folder 53)
    - RSNA (Box 10, Folder 54)
    - BPI (Box 10, Folder 55)
    - Vail Creative Concepts (Box 10, Folder 56)
    - American Express (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - External Review for Diag. Rad. 1987 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - PSR Board Meeting 1987 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Fulbright Program 1987 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - AAAS Annual Mtg. 1987 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Univ. of Pennsylvania 1987 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Soc. Of Cardiovas. & Interv. Radiology 1987 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Dr. Peter Bing luncheon 1987 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Lunch + Seminar April 20, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - American Roentgen Ray Society 1987 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - AUR Meeting 1987 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Jack Campbell Lecture 1987 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - North American Soc. Card. Rad. 1987 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - IPPNW 7th World Congress 1987 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - AOA Visiting Professorship (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Medical Staff Dinner Mtg 1987 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Harvard Course 1987 (2nd folder) (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Institute for the Humanities 1987 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - PSR Bay Area Benefit Dinner 1987 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Herbert L. Abrams Lecture 1987 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Vail Creative Concepts 1987 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - RSNA 1987 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Medicine for the 21st Century 1988 (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Medical School All Day Course 1988 (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Medical School Talk on PSR-IPPNW 1988 (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - SCVIR Dotter Lecture 1988 (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - PSR National Meeting 1987 (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - Thoracic Imaging 1988 (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - The Development of a Cons. Conf. 1988 (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - Clin. Pathologic Conference 1988 (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - North Am. Soc. For Cardiac Rad. 1988 (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - Hodes Lecture 1988 (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - Personal Writing (Box 11, Folder 33)
    - Personal Correspondence Prior to 1956 (Box 11, Folder 34)
    - Personal Correspondence 1956 (Box 11, Folder 35)
    - Personal Correspondence 1957-1959 (Box 11, Folder 36)
    - Personal Correspondence 1960-1961 + ELG (Box 11, Folder 37)
    - Personal Correspondence 1962-1964 (Box 11, Folder 38)
    - Personal Correspondence 1965-1967 (Box 11, Folder 39)
    - Personal Correspondence 1968-1970 (Box 11, Folder 40)
    - Personal Correspondence 1971 (Box 11, Folder 41)
    - Kaplan, Dr. Henry S. (Box 11, Folder 42)
    - Dotter, Charles (Box 11, Folder 43)
  - Papers and Civil Defense Papers and Readings
    - Ebert, Dr. Robert (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Manuscript Roentgenology Cardiac Pacemakers Dr. Tegtmeyer (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Maunscript A Season of Paradox. Abrams (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Manuscript/Speech A Season of Change: Legacy of the Sixties (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Primary (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Manuscript: The Pathologic & Prognostic Implications of Coronary Arteriography (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Biplane Eleven Inch Image Intensified Cinefluorography (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - from dr. hessel 8/7 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - China Chronicle April, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Nuclear War Civil Defense (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Civil Defense (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Civil Defense (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Speech "The Politics of Survival" (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Civil Defense (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Civ Def (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Civil Defense (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Civil Defense—Switzerland (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Civil Defense—Sweden (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Civil Defense—Soviet Union (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Candidate U.S. Civil Defense Programs (binder) (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Security of Nuclear and Chemical Weapons Storage (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Nuc. Mat. Sec. Drafts & Notes (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Security Weapons/Fuel (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Regan Book Text (1) (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Regan Book Text (2) (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Regan Book Text (3) (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Regan Book Text (4) (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Regan Book Text (5) (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Regan Book Text (6) (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Regan Book Text (7) (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Regan Book Text (8) (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Regan Book Text (9) (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Regan Book Text (10) (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Regan Book Text (11) (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Regan Book Text (12) (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Regan Book Text (13) (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Draft Interviews (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Transition and Hinkley Poland (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - 2. Medical Society (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - The President's Men III (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Regan: Guidelines for Success 4A (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Confusion 4B (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Was the President in Danger? 4C (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Capacity for Decision Making (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - The Failure to Invoke the 25th Amendment (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - The Next Time (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Development of the 25th (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Other Issues (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Harvard Medical School
    - 4 binders: 1977-1979 (Box 14)
    - 3 binders and one spiral bound book: 1979-1891 (Box 15)
  - Interviews and notebooks
    - Interviews conducted for The President Has Been Shot: Disability, Confusion and the 25th Amendment (1992), 1988-1990; 12 audiocassette(s); 3 audiocassette(s) (microcassette) (Box 16)
    - Spiral notebooks (approx 27), 1973-1980 (Box 16)
  - Nuclear Weapons and Gulf War Reference Documents and Writings (Box 17)
- Papers, Accession ARCH-2007-111
  - Yalta
    - Background/general
      - (Yalta) bibliography (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - (Yalta) chronology (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - (Yalta) maps (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - (Yalta) notes (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Yalta general
      - Yalta general (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Yalta general (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Yalta general (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Diplomatic Papers- Malta and Yalta (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Documents- Yalta
      - (Yalta) British docs (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - (Yalta) documents (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - (Yalta) documents (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Pre-Yalta
      - Pre-Yalta (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Road to Yalta (1/3) (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Road to Yalta (2/3) (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Road to Yalta (3/3) (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - United Nations before Yalta (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - (Yalta) preliminary overview (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Post-Yalta
      - Post-Yalta (general) (Box 1, Folder 18)
      - Post-Yalta research notes (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - Post-Yalta research planning (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Roosevelt and Yalta
      - (Yalta) Evans on Roosevelt (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Roosevelt after Yalta (biographies, heads of state, family) (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Roosevelt @ Yalta (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Records
      - Official British record: Yalta (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - Official US record: Yalta (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - Official US record: Yalta (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - (Yalta) Russian record (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - (Yalta) Soviet archives (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - (Yalta) Soviet archives (file # 2) (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Yalta A-D
      - Yalta A-B (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - Yalta C-D (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Yalta E-L
      - Yalta E-F (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - Yalta G-H (Box 2, Folder 13)
      - Yalta I-L (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Yalta M-Z
      - Yalta M-N (Box 2, Folder 15)
      - Yalta O-P (Box 2, Folder 16)
      - Yalta Q-R (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - Yalta S-T (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - Yalta U-Z (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Yalta- miscellaneous
      - (Yalta) Europe (Box 2, Folder 20)
      - (Yalta) Far East (Box 2, Folder 21)
      - (Yalta) Poland Draft (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Yalta memoirs
      - Yalta memoirs (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Yalta News
      - Articles Yalta (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Yalta newspapers (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Yalta
      - Yalta (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Yalta (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Cognition/Decision-making
    - Cognitive effects
      - Anxiety, depression, memory and cognition (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - (Cognitive effects) Aging (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - (Cognitive) aging (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - (Cognitive) blood loss, transfusions, oxygen (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - (Cognitive) blood loss, transfusions, oxygen deprivation (cont'd) (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - (Cognitive) cancer (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - (Cognitive) depression (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - GI disease (cognitive) (Box 3, Folder 12)
      - Cognitive: Hypertension (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - Cognitive effects/illness (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - Cognitive: medications (Box 3, Folder 15)
      - Radiation effects: speech (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - Cognitive: strokes (Box 3, Folder 17)
      - Cognitive: trauma (Box 3, Folder 18)
      - Cognitive stress as cause of illness (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Cognitive: sick state and surgery (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Crisis Decision-making
      - Leaders and crisis decision-making (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - Crisis decision-making (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Will presidents use nuclear weapons? (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Decision-makers: cognitive
      - Stress: Cognitive decision-making (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - Decision making, aging and pain (Box 4, Folder 7)
      - Decision making (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Human fallibility
      - Human fallibility (Box 4, Folder 9)
      - Human fallibility: Cognitive- heart disease (Box 4, Folder 10)
      - Working papers: human instability, disability, accidental nuclear war (Box 4, Folder 11)
      - Human fallibility: cognitive and alcohol (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Leadership and disability
      - Notes from Post and Robbins (Box 4, Folder 13)
      - Leaders and cognitive impairment (Box 4, Folder 14)
      - Leaders and mental illness (Box 4, Folder 15)
      - [Photocopied sources] (Box 4, Folder 16)
      - Presidents and use of force (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - World leaders
      - Mitterand (Box 4, Folder 18)
      - Other sick leaders (Box 4, Folder 19)
      - "Patterns of death in world leaders" (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Fiske: adult images (Box 4, Folder 21)
      - Slides: Cognitive (Box 4, Folder 22)
      - [Photocopied sources] (Box 4, Folder 23)
      - Reviews: miscellaneous sources (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Decision Makers/Soviet Leaders (3:2)
    - Decision makers (#1) (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Decision makers (#2) (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Decision makers (#3) (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Decision makers (general/misc) (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Decision makers: Proposal (to the John D. and Catherine T. MacArthur Fund: Sources of Human Instability and Disability in Decision Makers) (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - "The Decline of Age- Woodrow Wilson" (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Human Instability Among Decision Makers (bibliography) (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Personality and Events (leaders) (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Saccharov (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Soviet Leaders- Health (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Accidents- Nuclear
    - Accidents: general (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Accidents: general research (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Accidents: lectures/chapters (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Accidental nuclear war: Irrevocable evil (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Accidental nuclear war: Pugwash Conference (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Chernobyl (1/3) (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Chernobyl (2/3) (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Chernobyl (3/3) (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Chernobyl incident (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Nuclear proliferation (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Nuclear weapons accident (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Nuclear weapons accident (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Prevention of accidents/nuclear war (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - References (for long paper) (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Accidents/unintended scenarios: Max Sullivan (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Slides and tabular material: accidental nuclear war (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Space and warfare accidents (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Star Wars (accidental) (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Technical/component failure (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Presidential Health
    - Conversations
      - Conversation with Lawrence Altman (May 19 1993) (Box 5, Folder 23)
      - Interview with Lawrence Mohr (White House) (Box 5, Folder 24)
      - Conversation with Jerry Post (June 23 1993) (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Disability
      - Disability (pres/VP) (Box 5, Folder 26)
      - Disability and presidents (Box 5, Folder 27)
      - Disability in presidents and Secretary of Defense (Box 5, Folder 28)
      - My summary of disability (Box 5, Folder 29)
      - Presidential Disability (Box 5, Folder 30)
      - Reviews of books on presidential disability (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Presidents
      - Bush and hyperthyroidism (Box 5, Folder 32)
      - Dole articles/health (Box 5, Folder 33)
      - Dole health (1/2) (Box 5, Folder 34)
      - Dole health (2/2) (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - Eisenhower: major events/sick presidents (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Presidential health
      - Presidents' health (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - Presidential health: choosing a healthy president (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - Presidential Health Conference at the Kennedy School (March 93) (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - Presidential health (misc.) (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - Presidential health (pre-20 cent) (Box 6, Folder 7)
      - Presidential health summaries (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Presidential health (misc.)
      - "A Heartbeat Away" (Box 6, Folder 10)
      - Articles (Box 6, Folder 11)
      - (Presidential health) articles (Box 6, Folder 12)
      - Candidates' health (Box 6, Folder 13)
      - Candidates' health (general) (Box 6, Folder 14)
      - Health statistics (Box 6, Folder 15)
      - Medical care of the VIP (Box 6, Folder 16)
      - Medical cover-ups (Box 6, Folder 17)
      - Political Psychology- 1994 (articles on presidential health) (Box 6, Folder 18)
      - I.O.M. Workshop: Stalking Behavior (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Presidential Illness
      - Presidential Illness and decision-making (Box 6, Folder 20)
      - Sick presidents and crises (Box 6, Folder 21)
      - Speech: illness and decision-making (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Presidential Physician
      - Presidential physician (Box 6, Folder 23)
      - Presidents' physician (Box 6, Folder 24)
      - Presidents' physician (Box 6, Folder 25)
      - White House physician (Dan Ruge's source material) (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Effects of Radiation
    - Biological effects: Effects on Humans
      - Biological effects on humans (Box 6, Folder 27)
      - Radiation: biological effects (Box 6, Folder 28)
      - Radiation: Occupational health hazards (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Burns
      - Burns (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Casualty statistics
      - Casualties due to blast, heat, fallout (Box 6, Folder 31)
      - Casualty estimates- FEMA (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Chronic Diseases
      - Chronic diseases in the US (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - Post-attack: communicable diseases (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Effects: general
      - Psychiatric effects (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - Radiation and cancer (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Hazards of radiation
      - Radiation hazard: epidemiology (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - Radiation hazard: FSU problems (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - Radiation hazard: wastes (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Human radiation experiments
      - Advisory committee on human radiation exposure (Box 7, Folder 8)
      - Human radiation experiment (Box 7, Folder 9)
      - Human radiation experiment (Box 7, Folder 10)